本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
你被监视着
You are being watched.
■
・ 翻译  阿好
・ 翻译  麦结
■
・ 翻译  卫老哥
・ 翻译  茶炒栗子
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
■
・ 翻译  宅女之后
・ 翻译  艾瑞卡
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
■
翻  幸田实果子
译  灰灰是菇凉
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror,
■
・ 校对  阿好
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
■
压制  灰灰是菇凉
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
violent crimes involving ordinary people.
凭陵新月  阿包  兜爹  Sage  烟幕迟迟  凭陵新月  阿包  兜爹  Sage  烟幕迟迟  凭陵新月  阿包  兜爹  Sage  烟幕迟迟
■
时间轴
政府认为这些人无关紧要
The government considers these people irrelevant.
我们不
We don't.
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You will never find us.
特效
灰灰
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
总监
阿好
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪
第三季第十八集
■
检测到异常
位置  伊拉克摩苏尔
摩苏尔变电站过载
电力网即将瘫痪
电力网瘫痪
事故分析
摩苏尔
位置 摩苏尔大坝
发电机丢失
数量  6
纽约
小熊
Bear!
不不不
No, no, no.
他找到宝贝了
He found the treats.
好啦  走啦
Come on. Go!
人家是军犬啊  芬奇
He's a military working dog, Finch.
搜查营救
Search and rescue,
专业受训追踪敌人  查找爆炸物啊
trained to track people, uncover explosives.
难怪[法国作家]莫里哀不堪一击
I suppose Moliere is no challenge at all.
也许我应该派小熊去追踪肖女士
Maybe I should have Bear track down Ms. Shaw.
你不是让她查新号码了
I thought you put her on the new number.
没错  但她就是拒绝通讯
I did, but communication is not her strong suit.
吁  芬奇
Tally-ho, Finch.
发现工程师
Our engineer's in sight.
这些涡轮叶片还没报关
These turbine blades are missing a customs clearance.
一到肯尼亚
As soon as they get to Kenya,
那边肯定要索贿才肯抬手
the locals will demand a bribe to clear them.
不过  我们没时间了
But, since we're out of time,
打电话给[肯尼亚]蒙巴萨海关的贝尼
call Benny at the Mombasa customs house.
告诉他有瓶肯塔基波本威士忌
Tell him there's a bottle of Kentucky Bourbon
玛丽亚・马丁内斯
手机被复制
是给他的
with his name on it.
联系人
手机被复制
这姑娘的外国联系人
Our girl's got more foreign contacts
比我和里瑟加起来还多
than Reese and I combined.
的确  玛丽亚・马丁内斯行踪遍及全球
Indeed. Maria Martinez is quite the world traveler.
斯坦福大学的工程硕士
Masters in engineering from Stanford.
她为水力集团工作  一家私人能源公司
She works for Hydral Corp, a private energy company.
她目前正在做
She's currently working on
第三世界国家的重建项目
reconstruction projects in third-world countries.
挖井么
She digs wells?
是建价值亿万美元的发电机
Builds multimillion-dollar generators is more like it.
她上一个项目是为一座位于伊拉克的
Her last project was replacing the generators
水力集团
能源电力  尽在掌握
水电站大坝重装发电机
inside a hydroelectric dam in Iraq.
玛丽亚
Maria!
加GPS追踪器这事  干得好
Great work here, adding the GPS trackers.
鉴于我们之前
Considering everything we went through
把这些发电机运送出国组装的惨痛经历
to get those generators into the country and assemble them.
可不能再像伊拉克一样了  丢不起了
Can't afford to lose anything, like we did in Iraq.
我们必须确保供应链和来源
We have to make sure our supply chain and sources
不容置疑
are beyond reproach.
那位是肯・戴维斯  玛丽亚的老板
That's Ken Davis, Maria's boss.
水力集团的负责人
He runs Hydral Corp.
失陪一下  我得接个电话
Excuse me, I have to take this.
喂
Hello?
你好
?????? ????
?????? ??????
包裹准备好了
The package is ready.
但我们不能在电话里说
But we can't talk on the phone.
一小时后老地方见
Meet at the usual place in an hour.
好
Yeah.
这可真没想到
Didn't see that comin'.
玛丽亚刚刚顺了一台GPS追踪器
Maria just took a five-finger discount on a GPS tracker.
抱歉  我得走了
I'm sorry, I have to go.
还好吗
Everything all right?
跟供应商的会议  我之前给忘了
Just a meeting with a supplier I forgot about.
-好的  -谢谢
- Okay. - Thank you.
还对她上司说了谎
And she lied to her boss.
再加上那个神秘包裹
Plus this delivery of a mysterious package?
像是前期筹备阶段战术
Sounds like pre-operational tactics.
战术  筹备什么
Tactics? Of what?
恐怖分子团伙
A terrorist cell.
玛丽亚要是相关号码
If Maria were a relevant number,
会被转到政府方面
she would fall under the government's purview.
没准儿机器搭错线了
Maybe the machine got its wires crossed.
自从它勾搭上那飞越疯人院的耳蜗女
Ever since it's had that Cochlear Cuckoo on speed dial--
我没看出此事跟格罗夫斯女士
I fail to see how its relationship with Ms. Groves
有任何关系
has anything to do with this.
你真的认为这号码有可能是恐怖分子吗
Do you really think that our number could be a terrorist?
我确信肖需要支援
I believe Shaw's gonna need our backup.
你好啊  哈罗德
Hello, Harold.
你想跟我说话吗  或者跟她
You wanted to talk to me? Or her?
你是怎么  当我没问
How did you-- never mind.
我想知道
I was curious--
我对你的小小号码毫不知情  哈罗德
I don't know anything about your little number, Harold.
我正在追踪更重要的目标
I'm pursing a much larger objective.
德西玛偷走的芯片
The chip that Decima stole.
是机器安排你
Has the machine directed you to--
那芯片已经重新设计
That chip has already been back-engineered
我们说话这会儿  正在被成千上万地复制
and thousands of copies are being generated as we speak.
功率足够运行"撒马利亚人"了
Enough to run Samaritan at full power.
机器警示我
The machine has alerted me
咱们那位神秘对手回城了
that our elusive adversary is back in town.
除掉他可能是我们阻止
Eliminating him might be our last chance
"撒马利亚人"的最后机会了
at stopping Samaritan.
保持联络  等我下次耳朵发痒再聊
I'll be in touch the next time my ear starts burning.
知道我的位置吗
Do you have my position?
很好  我交了个新朋友
Good. I've made a new friend,
但我现在不太想寒暄
but I'm not feeling particularly sociable.
切断帕克赫斯特的监控
Have our asset at Parkhurst security go blind.
信号丢失
■
追踪主体
化名  格里尔  约翰
监控摄像头离线
切换至音频
追踪主体
化名  格里尔  约翰
监控摄像头离线
切换至音频
重量
间隔
距离
音频分析
84.024公斤
1.023秒
0.976米
再次捕获目标
方向
Direction?
收到
Got it.
麻烦来点噪音
A little volume, please.
追踪主体
化名  格里尔  约翰
重量
84.024公斤
间隔
1.023秒
距离
0.976米
音频输入饱和
失去目标
转换到GPS
搜索中...
再次捕获目标
你在这儿
There you are.
切断联络
Going dark.
两分钟后指定地点见面
Rendezvous in two minutes.
干什么啊  女士
What the hell, lady?
抱歉
Sorry.
把你当成我叔叔了
Thought you were my uncle.
[黎巴嫩首都]贝鲁特
Beirut.
-巴格达  -巴格达的烤鱼
- Baghdad. - Baghdad for Masguf.
萨达姆真心懂鱼
Saddam knew his fish.
这个没错
I'll give you that.
但是烤羊肉
But Shawarma?
贝鲁特  妥妥的
Beirut, hands down.
他不能回去
He can't go back.
我已经拼尽全力了
I'm doing everything I can.
他们就是不放他
They won't release him.
我们现在必须有所行动
We must do something now.
我追踪了玛丽亚之前的电话
I traced Maria's earlier phone call.
贾马尔・瑞沙是伊拉克人  两年前移民到美国
Jamal Risha is an Iraqi who immigrated to the U.S. two years ago.
那个人  他不见我
This man, he won't see me.
他甚至不跟我谈
He won't even talk to me.
他是困住奥马尔的唯一因素
He's the only thing blocking Omar.
我们不能抛下我的兄弟
We can't just leave my brother behind.
芬奇  你听到了吗
Finch, you hear that?
根据移民和海关执法局的数据
According to the Immigration and Customs Enforcement database,
奥马尔・瑞沙一周前在肯尼迪机场一降落
Omar Risha was detained by the Department of Homeland Security
扣留  特别行政措施
就被国土安全部扣留了
after landing at JFK a week ago.
他们现在把他关押在哪里
Where are they holding him now?
依照特别行政措施被关押在曼哈顿
A high-security detention center in Manhattan
一间高度戒备拘留所
under special administrative measures.
那里专门关押恐怖主义嫌犯
Those are reserved for terrorism suspects.
我们影响他们的机会很渺茫
We have a small window of opportunity to make an impact.
这应该能引起他们注意
This should open their eyes.
大炸弹总是来自小包裹
Big bombs keep coming in little packages.
比如扔鞋弹者
Like the shoe bomber.
祝你平安
?? ?????
谢谢  贾马尔
????? ????
我盯贾马尔
I'll keep eyes on Jamal.
看他还有没有别的联络人
See if he has any other contacts.
我去跟紧这位玛丽亚
I'll stick close to our friend Maria.
查清她这是搅了什么浑水
Figure out what the hell she's gotten herself into.
多谢你的三明治
Thanks for the sandwich.
不过你把我拽到这儿干嘛
But why do you gotta drag me all the way up here,
干看那位姑娘拍照留念么
just to watch your girl snap a few memories?
你几时见过城区纽约人
When's the last time you saw a New Yorker from the village
到联合国这儿旅游拍照了
take tourist photos at the U.N.?
有道理
That's a good point.
你这么聪明  还要我干嘛
If you're so smart, what do you need me for?
这儿不能停车
You can't park here!
安全预防
Security precaution.
知道  我有这个
Yeah, I got one of those.
瞧你多有用  莱奈尔
Way to make yourself useful, Lionel.
我真不明白联合国是干嘛吃的
You know, I don't understand all the hoopla with the U.N. anyway.
要我说  就是一群阔佬官僚
Bunch of silver-spoon bureaucrats, if you ask me.
更别提那个扯蛋的
And don't even get me started
治外法权了
with the extraterritorial privileges either.
联合国区域非美国领土  纽约警察无执法权
我就该直接偷个警徽得了
I should've just stolen a badge.
你说联合国里有多少国家
How many countries you think there are in the U.N.?
-50个有吗  -193个
- Like 50-something? - 193.
你没事儿多出去走走
You know, you really should get out more.
了解他国文化
Learn something about other cultures.
瞧你这话说的
What are you talking about?
我刚吃了个中东炸丸子
I just ate a falafel.
是啊  都吃到领带上了
Yeah, and you got some on your tie.
这周第二条了
That's the second tie this week.
玛丽亚在拍摄联合国大厦的内部
Maria's taking photos of the interior of the U.N. Compound.
监视是袭击之前的最后一步
Surveillance is the last planning stage before an attack.
等等
Wait.
她不是在拍大厦
She's not shooting the compound.
她是在拍这个人
She's taking pictures of this guy.
照片给你发过去了  芬奇
Photo's on its way, Finch.
不知道这穿西装的是谁
I don't know who the suit is.
照片中的人是雷内・拉波因特
The man in the photo is Rene Lapointe:
一名法国外交官
a French diplomat and
现在是联合国难民高级专员
current United Nations high commissioner for refugees.
联合国难民高级专员  雷内・拉波因特
他负责批准贾马尔的兄弟奥马尔的
He's responsible for approving the asylum request
庇护请求
of Jamal's brother Omar.
他刚刚激活了咱们的"圣战珍妮"
He just triggered our Jihad Jane to go live.
美国著名的本土女恐怖分子
玛丽亚截住了他的车  她安了个东西
Maria just stopped his car. She's putting something--
肖女士  是什么
Miss Shaw, what is it?
高  实在是高
That was smooth.
我出手也不过如此了
I couldn't have done that better myself.
她刚把GPS追踪器放到了拉波因特的车上
She just placed the GPS tracker onto Lapointe's limo.
她在跟踪他
She's tracking him.
出租车
Taxi!
更重要的是
And, more importantly...
我们找到她的目标了
I think we just identified her target.
那些有权有势的外交官周游世界
All these fat-cat diplomats travel all over the world,
拿着别人的钱吃吃喝喝
eatin' on someone else's dime
还满嘴说要救济穷人
while they talk about feeding the poor.
也许你该考虑去申请张护照了
Maybe you ought to consider applying for a passport.
我有护照
I have a passport.
我和我前妻去圣托马斯岛渡的蜜月
My ex and I went to Saint Thomas for our honeymoon.
你是说美属维尔京群岛吧
You mean the U.S. Virgin Islands?
好了  她来了
Okay, there's our girl.
这位工程师换装还真快
Your engineer pulls one hell of a changing act.
对  换杀人装了
Yeah, dressed to kill.
包裹还在她的单肩包里
She's still got that package in her shoulder bag.
去吧  我盯着前门
Go ahead, I'll watch the front.
我们有麻烦了  芬奇
We might have a problem, Finch.
玛丽亚正在接近她的目标
Maria's closing in on her target.
你想要证据吗  这就是证据
You want proof? There's proof.
情况还好吗  肖女士
Is everything all right, Ms. Shaw?
虚惊一场
False alarm.
最多不过是被纸割伤
Unless we're worried about paper cuts.
抱歉  我认识你吗
Sorry, do I know you?
奥马尔・瑞沙不是恐怖分子
Omar Risha is not a terrorist.
他为驻伊美军和我们公司担任翻译
He worked for U.S. Forces in Iraq and for my company as a translator.
这是我老板肯・戴维斯的推荐信
There's a recommendation in here from my boss Ken Davis.
你还想要什么证据
What more proof do you want?
水力集团
我猜猜
Let me guess.
-你一定是玛丽亚了  -正是
- You must be Maria? - In person.
玛丽亚  美国国土安全部要求我
Maria, the U.S. Department of Homeland Security has asked me
在确认难民身份前要权衡所有证据
to weigh all the evidence before classifying refugees.
你有什么证据能证明他是恐怖分子
What evidence do you have to the contrary?
这是机密
That is confidential.
但我向你保证
But, let me assure you,
奥马尔・瑞沙会得到公正的听证
Omar Risha will have a fair hearing.
我先失陪了
Now if you'll excuse me.
我懂
Look, I get it.
直说吧
Just tell me...
要多少钱
What's the going rate?
你疯了吗
Are you insane?
不给我答复  我不会离开
I am not leaving until I get an answer.
-保安  -抱歉  女士
- Security! - Excuse me, ma'am.
请跟我们走
Please come with us.
抱歉  先生们
Sorry, gentlemen.
她跟我一起的
She's with me.
没事  我认识她
It's okay, I know her.
让我来处理吧
Allow me to take care of this.
芬奇
Finch?
玛丽亚正要被架出去
Maria was about to get tossed out
发件人: 未知
收件人: 未知
这个男人出手了
when this guy stepped in.
发件人: 未知
收件人: 未知
你和肯・戴维斯共事
You work with Ken Davis.
他是我朋友
He's a friend.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry about all this.
真不想给你添麻烦
I don't wanna burden you with my problems.
怎么回事
What's this all about?
我在伊拉克的翻译被指涉嫌恐怖主义被拘留了
My former interpreter from Iraq is being held on suspicion of terrorism
可能会被遣返
and might be deported.
那指控是子虚乌有
I know it's a false allegation.
但那混蛋不相信我
But that jerk won't believe me.
拉波因特先生是有点懒惰  甚至腐败
Monsieur Lapointe may be lazy, even corrupt,
不过当老好人是爬不到那个位置的
but you don't get all that power by being a nice guy.
对付他这种人有很多方法
There are ways around men like him.
我不知道还有什么路
I don't know what else to do.
也许我可以帮忙
Perhaps I can help.
没有水力集团这样的公司建设基础设施
Without companies like Hydral Corp that build infrastructure,
联合国可办不成任何事
the United Nations would never accomplish anything.
不幸的是  有些保守派
Unfortunately, some of the old guard
就喜欢恩将仇报
prefer to bite the hand that feeds.
我打几个电话吧
Let me make a few calls.
如果你还有其他需要
If you need anything else...
谢谢
Thank you.
玛丽亚似乎找到了救星
Looks like Maria just found herself a White Knight.
克里斯托・斯凡
Christos Sevon,
希腊一位职业外交官
A career diplomat from Greece
目前供职于联合国可持续能源计划
currently serving on the U.N. sustainable energy program.
他的工作是募集资金支持重建项目
He raises funds to support reconstruction projects
就像玛丽亚他们公司在伊拉克的工作
like the one Maria worked on in Iraq.
他说愿意帮助奥马尔入境
He's offered to help get Omar into the country.
但愿这决定不会让他悔恨终生
Let's hope that he doesn't live to regret that decision.
我们得看看那份指证奥马尔的证据
We need to get a look at that evidence against Omar.
看来奥马尔需要一位好律师
Sounds like Omar could use a good lawyer.
扣留  特别行政措施
看来里瑟先生和我要提供点法律援助服务了
Perhaps it's time Mr. Reese and I did a little pro bono work.
你和你的同伴有什么需要我帮忙的  翠鸟先生
How can I help you and your associates, Mr. Kingfisher?
我的事务所代理了几位难民
My firm represents several refugees
他们在伊拉克为美国政府工作
who worked for the U.S. government in Iraq
正在寻求庇护
now seeking asylum.
我们对于伊拉克难民移民美国有一些顾虑
There are concerns about refugees from Iraq immigrating to the U.S.
是的  我们知道
Yes, we're--we're aware.
我们的客户之一  奥马尔・瑞沙
One of our clients-- Omar Risha
由于被指涉嫌与恐怖分子有关而被扣留了
is being detained for alleged links to terrorism.
我很熟悉瑞沙先生的案子
I know Monsieur Risha's case well.
实际上  我这周就必须做出最终裁决
In fact, I have to make a final decision on it this week.
我能看看吗
May I?
要准备法律辩护
If I'm to prepare a legal defense,
我得查阅所有资料
I require all of the facts.
你可以看资料  但只能在这里
You may review it, but here.
谢谢
Thank you.
上周我收到了来自伊拉克政府的信
I received that letter from the Iraqi government last week.
内政部说他们有证据显示
The Ministry of the Interior say they have proof
奥马尔涉嫌恐怖活动
that Omar is involved in terrorist activity.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
伊拉克内政部可不怎么可信
The Ministry of the Interior is hardly reliable.
里面都是前什叶派武装组织的成员
It's full of former Shia Militia members.
他们把帮助美军的伊拉克人都视为叛徒
They view Iraqis that helped American forces as traitors.
三年前  两名在伊拉克杀过美国士兵的恐怖分子
Three years ago, two terrorists who killed U.S. soldiers in Iraq
被发现住在肯塔基州鲍灵格林
were discovered living in Bowling Green, Kentucky.
他们假装是前翻译骗过了移民官员
They fooled immigration officials by posing as former interpreters.
是的  不过  孤立的案件
Yes, but, surely, such an isolated case
不应该影响成千上万的其他申请
should not affect the plight of thousands.
我不能冒险批准
I can't afford to put my signature
一名潜在恐怖分子的申请
on an application of a potential terrorist,
不管可能性多小
however small the probability.
如果再有恐怖分子趁虚而入
If one more terrorist slips through,
就会伤害其他所有寻求庇护的难民
it will jeopardize all the other refugees seeking asylum.
你懂的
You understand.
懂
Understood.
-非常感谢  -谢谢
- Thank you for your time. - Thank you.
很难确定信件的真实性
It's difficult to determine the authenticity of the letter.
你那边有新进展吗  肖女士
Any new developments on your end, Ms. Shaw?
她坐七号线回家  算进展不
She takes the 7 train to get home. Does that help?
贾马尔  好消息
Jamal, good news.
我找到合适的人帮我们了
I found someone in a position we can leverage.
回我电话  我们详谈
Call me back, and I'll explain.
谢谢
Thank you.
[法语]不客气
De rien.
你有多少备用枪弹
How many extra mags you got?
备用枪弹  你开玩笑吗
Extra mags? You serious?
芬奇  我们需要支援了
Finch, we're gonna need some backup.
不介意吧
Mind?
个人来说  我比较喜欢氯化钾而不是氯仿
Personally, I prefer potassium chloride to chloroform.
起效快  尸检查不出来
Acts quicker and no trace in postmortem toxicology.
氯仿还有一个问题  太臭
And the other thing about chloroform, it stinks.
那是谁
Who the hell was that?
阿尔及利亚裔法国人
French Algerian.
意大利著名刀具品牌
还带着马塞里刀
With a Maserin bolt knife.
我看是法国外籍兵团的
I'd say French Foreign Legion.
世界著名佣兵组织
你还真是朋友遍天下  玛丽亚
You've made friends all over the world, Maria.
外籍兵团
Foreign Legion?
他们为什么会想杀我
Why would they wanna kill me?
不知道  不会法语
I don't know. I don't speak French.
芬奇  美国队长什么时候到
Finch, what's our ETA on Captain America?
里瑟先生马上就到
Mr. Reese should be with you directly.
贴紧墙
Stay close to the wall.
这家伙应该有帮手
I'm guessing this guy might have some friends.
[法语]撤
Allons-y.
看来中东炸丸子没拖住你啊
Guess that falafel didn't slow you down.
就这些吗  还有吗
Is that it? Any more?
玛丽亚  趴下
Maria, get down!
你们家小子有问题
Your boy there's got issues.
但愿那家伙有医保
Hope that guy has health insurance.
美国冒险运动家  世界头号飞人
你那空中飞人怎么玩儿的
What's up with the Evel Knievel stunt?
海军小学没教你吗
They didn't teach you that in marine jump school?
子弹又不是搞不定
Only if a 5-cent piece of lead won't get you out the door.
-不过感谢前来  -不客气
- But thanks for coming. - You're welcome.
很抱歉打扰一下  但你们是谁
I'm sorry to interrupt, but who the hell are you guys?
我们跟你很像  马丁内斯女士
We're a lot like you, Ms. Martinez.
我们帮助那些处境不幸的人
We help people in less fortunate circumstances.
我们只要求一项回报
We only require one thing in return for our services.
什么
What's that?
真相
The truth.
你为什么想要奥马尔・瑞沙来美国
Why are you trying to get Omar Risha into the U.S.?
奥马尔是我上一个项目的翻译
Omar was my interpreter on my last project.
我们在运送六台发电机
We were in a convoy transporting six generators
从科威特到伊拉克的路上中了埋伏
from Kuwait to Iraq when we were ambushed.
我跳进一条沟里  眼看没希望了
I jumped into a ditch, about to be overrun,
奥马尔跳到我身边
when Omar jumped in next to me
开枪打死了两名恐怖分子
and shot two of the terrorists.
其他的逃跑了
The rest fled.
他救了我的命
He saved my life.
似乎该给他发个勋章
Sounds like he deserves a medal.
我离开伊拉克后  奥马尔就开始收到死亡威胁
After I left Iraq, Omar started receiving death threats.
如果他被遣回  他会被杀死的
If he's sent back, he'll be killed.
法国兵团跟这有什么关系
What do French Legionnaires have to do with this?
我不知道
I don't know.
奥马尔离开之前  想要谈谈
The day before Omar left, he wanted to talk to me
在伊拉克丢失的那些发电机的事
about some generators that went missing in Iraq.
他不想在电话里说
He didn't wanna talk about it on the phone.
伊拉克内政部给联合国发了这封信
The Iraqi Ministry of the Interior sent this letter to the U.N.
说奥马尔和恐怖组织有关
Stating that Omar has links to terrorist groups.
这不是真的
This is not true.
为什么会有人这么做
Why would someone do this?
弗斯科警探逮捕了那名受伤的外籍兵团成员
Detective Fusco arrested the injured legionnaire.
或许他醒来后可以回答这个问题
Perhaps, when he wakes up, he can answer that question.
他们可能是效命于外国情报机构
They could be working for a foreign intelligence service.
也可能是效命于联合国高级专员拉波因特
They could also be working for the U.N. high commissioner Lapointe.
他之前负责驻刚果的联合国维和部队
His last post was head of U.N. Peacekeeping in the Congo.
当时他的手下就包括法国外籍兵团
Among the units under his control was a company of French Legionnaires.
为什么拉波因特会因为我想让奥马尔来美国就杀我
Why would Lapointe wanna kill me for trying to help Omar get into the U.S.?
我们得和奥马尔谈谈
We need to talk to Omar.
他应该可以提供点线索
He could shed some light on this.
那不可能
It's impossible.
他被禁止通信
He's being held incommunicado.
我们不敢用政府指派的律师传信
We can't even trust his government-appointed lawyer to deliver a message.
或许他会跟他的新律师谈谈
Maybe he'll talk to his new representation.
我跟上一位律师也是这么说的  我不会开口
Like I told my last attorney, I'm not talking to you.
我们不是政府的人  瑞沙先生
We're not with the government, Mr. Risha.
我们是玛丽亚・马丁内斯的朋友
We're friends of Maria Martinez.
也许你和陷害我的人是一伙儿的
Or maybe you work with the people that are setting me up.
玛丽亚告诉我们  在伊拉克时你救了她的命
Maria told us how you saved her life in Iraq.
抱歉我没有更多证据
I'm sorry I don't have more proof,
但我们时间不多了
but we don't have much time.
昨晚  一队外籍兵团的人
Last night, a team of legionnaires
企图杀害玛丽亚
made an attempt on Maria's life.
什么
What?
-她还好吗  -她没事
- Is she okay? - She's fine.
她现在在一个安全的地方
And she's in a safe place.
但你们上次通话时
But there was something important
你想告诉玛丽亚什么重要的事
you wanted to tell Maria during your last conversation?
关于发电机
About the generators.
是能源项目里的吗
The ones at the energy project
她在伊拉克工作时的
that she worked on in Iraq?
玛丽亚离开后
After Maria left,
发电机根本没装上
the generators were never installed.
水电站瘫痪了
The hydroelectric plant failed.
整个地区陷入黑暗
The entire province went dark.
医院没有电
Hospitals had no electricity.
病人死在手术台上
Patients died on operating tables.
当地警察控制不住局势
The local police lost control.
一周之内  基地组织就杀回来了
Within a week, Al-Qaeda moved back in.
发电机怎么了
What happened to the generators?
这正是我想告诉玛丽亚的
That's what I wanted to tell Maria.
就在我离开之前  我翻译了一份合同
Right before I left, I translated a contract
内容是转运那六台发电机
for the transportation of six generators.
合同是谁签的
A contract signed by whom?
你确定能保护好玛丽亚吗
Are you sure you can protect Maria?
是的
Yes.
怎么了
Why?
因为是她上司签的
Because it was her boss.
肯・戴维斯
Ken Davis.
戴维斯
Davis?
他为什么要把发电机运到伊拉克
Why would he ship generators all the way to Iraq
兜一圈又转运到他处呢
only to turn around and ship them somewhere else?
也许他得到了更高的报价
Maybe he got a better offer.
玛丽亚让戴维斯为你写了封推荐信
Maria had Davis write a letter of recommendation in your behalf.
他一定意识到
That must be where he realized that,
如果你俩重聚  你会告诉她
if the two of you were ever reunited, you would tell her
发电机的丢失跟他有关
about his involvement with the missing generators.
你的庇护请求被拒绝
Your asylum request has been denied.
一个小时后遣送你回家
Your ride home departs in an hour.
不  这是搞错了  拜托
No, this is a mistake. Please!
我回去  他们会杀了我
They'll kill me if I go back!
我刚发给你一条新线索  警探
I just sent you information on a new lead, Detective.
原来是玛丽亚的上司
It appears that Maria's boss redirected
把丢失的发电机转运到了未知地点
the missing generators in Iraq to an unknown destination.
他怎么做到的
How'd he do that?
我不确定  但奥马尔知道
I'm not sure, but Omar knew about it.
肯・戴维斯安排将他
Ken Davis arranged for him
遣返回伊拉克  他回去就会被杀
to be deported back to Iraq where he'll be killed.
戴维斯没那个权力啊
Davis doesn't have that kind of authority.
但他显然有办法
But he certainly has the resources
说服一名腐败的联合国外交官
to convince a corrupt U.N. diplomat
替他办妥此事
to do his dirty work.
是啊  看来我得拜访下戴维斯了
Yeah, I think I'm gonna have to pay Davis a visit.
请尽快  警探
Please hurry, Detective.
我们时间不多了
We haven't much time.
戴维斯为什么要偷发电机
Why would Davis steal the generators?
我们正在查
We're looking into that now.
我得去找奥马尔
I have to get to Omar.
你不能离开
You're not going anywhere
外籍兵团还在外面
with the Legionnaires still out there.
这里设计安装了装甲门
Guy engineered this place with an armored door
和电磁锁  你在这里很安全
and electromagnetic locks: you're safe here.
你不明白
You don't understand.
奥马尔一回伊拉克就会被杀
They will kill Omar if he returns to Iraq.
拜托了
Please.
你要哭吗
Are you gonna cry?
-什么  -等等
- What? - Hold on a sec.
你和奥马尔不只是生意同伴  是吧
You and Omar were more than just business associates, weren't you?
每次我遇到麻烦
Every time I ran into a problem--
酋长啊  部落啊  贪官啊
this sheikh, that tribe, this corrupt official--
都是奥马尔出面解决
it was always Omar who solved it
团结大家
by bringing people together.
所以我爱上了他
That's why I fell in love with him.
他会带我去夜晚的沙漠喝肉桂茶
He would take me to the desert at night to drink cinnamon tea
数星星
and count the stars.
你看到过夜晚的沙漠吗
Have you ever been to the desert at night?
我对沙漠的唯一记忆
The only thing I remember about the desert
是揭掉热骆驼奶上层的薄膜
is wiping the film off the top of a warm glass of camel's milk.
容易滋生细菌啊
That's where the bacteria breed.
好建议
Good advice.
奥马尔和我
Omar and I,
我们准备他一到就结婚
we hoped to get married when he got here.
他应该得到庇护
He deserves asylum.
我得阻止他被驱逐出境
I have to stop his deportation.
我必须去找他
I need to get to him.
玛丽亚  你得相信我们
Maria, you have to trust us.
为什么
Why?
我母亲曾是伊朗的一名学者
My mother was an academic back in Iran.
79年阿亚图拉和他手下的狂热分子接管了那里
When the Ayatollah and his fanatics took over in '79,
指1979年的伊朗伊斯兰革命
有人冒着生命危险偷偷带我妈妈离开
someone risked his life smuggling my mom out of there.
没有他
If it weren't for him --
你也不会来到这个世上
You'd have never been born.
那些差点让我妈妈死在伊朗的狂热分子
Those fanatics that could've killed my mom in Iran
就是那些等奥马尔回国就痛下杀手的狂热分子
are the same fanatics that will kill Omar if he returns to Iraq.
只是派系不同罢了
Just different stripes.
但我们不会让他们得逞的
But we're not gonna let that happen.
你们怎么阻止
How are you gonna stop it?
戴维斯收买了联合国外交官
Davis has a U.N. diplomat in his pocket
还有伊拉克政府的诬告
and false accusations from the Iraqi government.
你读过这个吗
Did you read this?
"据可靠消息  不容置疑
"According to a trusted source beyond reproach,
奥马尔・瑞沙牵涉"
Omar Risha has ties to--"
等等
Wait.
戴维斯的推荐信吗
Davis's recommendation?
"出于其绝对的正直度和诚信度
"because of his impeccable integrity and trustworthiness,
奥马尔的为人不容置疑"
Omar is a man beyond reproach."
两封都是戴维斯写的
Davis wrote both letters.
伊拉克政府的信纸
Iraqi government letterhead,
但是字体和
but the font and the...
格式都一样
the format are the same.
他伪造的
He forged it.
原件在拉波因特的办公室里
And the original is in Lapointe's office.
我得去拿
I have to get it.
你进不去
You can't get in there.
-不不  我认识人  我有办法  -玛丽亚
- No, no, I know someone. I know a way. - Maria.
你不能离开
You're not going anywhere.
你得相信我们
You have to trust us.
是的  玛丽亚・马丁内斯是我的员工
Yes, Maria Martinez is an employee of mine.
她出事了吗  警探
Something happen to her, Detective?
你是能源巨头  对吧
You're a big energy guy, right?
国际商人
International businessman?
有不少高层的朋友
Friends in high places?
联合国里也有人
Even the U.N.?
你不介意的话  恕我另有安排
If you don't mind, I have a schedule to keep.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
和你联合国的朋友
You have another meeting scheduled
又安排了会面吗
with your friend inside the U.N.?
你每天都联系的那位吗
The one you've been calling every day?
这是什么
What is this?
元数据吗
Metadata?
这严重侵犯了我的公民自由
This is a massive violation of my civil liberties.
我们已经申请了搜查证
We've already issued a warrant
因为你的腐败法国朋友拉波因特那
for your corrupt French pal Lapointe
因为你企图谋杀玛丽亚・马丁内斯
for the attempted murder of Maria Martinez.
他一滚蛋
As soon as he flips,
我们就能拿到你送去联合国
we'll have the forged document you sent to the U.N.
诬陷奥马尔・瑞沙为恐怖分子的伪造文件
naming Omar Risha a terrorist.
太荒谬了
This is absurd.
我的律师呢
Where's my attorney?
奥马尔发现了发电机的事
See, Omar found out about the generators.
你就要把他送回去  知道他回去会被杀
So you had him shipped back, knowing he'd be killed.
然后你还想杀害玛丽亚
Then you tried to kill Maria too.
据我所知
Last I checked,
你一名小小的纽约警察
Your little NYPD fiefdom
根本没有联合国区域的执法权
doesn't extend into the United Nations.
想用你的破警徽进去  那就祝你好运了  警探
Good luck using your tin badge to get in there, Detective.
你还真把自己当盘菜了
You really think you're a big shot, huh?
收买了几名官僚
Get a couple bureaucrats in your pocket,
合同能挣钱
grease the contracts.
你就完全不在乎他人死活
You don't care who dies.
包括你自己的员工
Including your own employees.
既然地检署没准备好起诉我的当事人  我们走
Unless the D.A.'s ready to charge my client, we're leaving.
想国际浑水
If you're going to wade into international waters,
警探  建议你换条大船吧
Detective, I suggest you get a bigger boat.
奥马尔有消息了吗
Any word on Omar?
我需要喝一杯
I could use a drink.
我也是
So could I.
我家那两位肯定藏了瓶纯麦芽威士忌
My boys keep a single malt in here somewhere.
谢天谢地  芬奇买的顶级好货
Thank God Finch buys top shelf.
芬奇
Finch!
电压过高
安全模式启动
门关闭
倒霉工程师
Damn engineers.
里瑟先生  他们要驱逐奥马尔
Mr. Reese, they're loading Omar for deportation.
我们得有所行动
We have to do something.
我跟上去
I'm going to pursue.
不用  芬奇  我搞定
No need, Finch. I'm on it.
开吧
Let's hit it.
收到
Roger that.
肖女士  好消息
Ms. Shaw, good news.
里瑟先生解救了奥马尔
Mr. Reese has rescued Omar.
太好了
That's great.
问题是玛丽亚丢了
Except we just lost Maria,
外籍兵团还在外面找她
and the Legionnaires are still out there looking for her.
更糟的是
And what's worse,
我看她是奔拉波因特的办公室去了
I think she's headed to Lapointe's office.
直入虎口啊
Straight into the lion's den.
拜托  我跟斯凡先生有约
Please, I have an appointment with Mr. Sevon.
他是希腊外交官  我时间紧迫
He's a Greek Diplomat. I don't have much time.
抱歉  女士  没有证件  不准进入
Sorry, Lady. No badge, no entry.
怎么回事
What's the problem here?
她是我的客人
She's my guest.
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
我们得抓紧了
We have to hurry.
玛丽亚  我说我能帮忙是指打几个电话
Maria, when I said I'd help, I meant making a few calls--
拉波因特拒绝奥马尔的庇护是因为
Lapointe denied Omar's asylum based on
一封来自伊拉克政府的伪造信件
a forged letter from the Iraqi government.
这封信现在在拉波因特的办公室  我得拿到
That letter is in Lapointe's office, and I need to get to it.
太荒谬了
This is absurd.
我们不能闯进高级专员的办公室
We can't just break into the high commissioner's office.
我们可以走正规渠道
There are proper channels we can follow.
戴维斯和拉波因特勾结要害死奥马尔
Davis conspired with Lapointe to have Omar killed.
他们还想要我的命
And now they want me dead too.
什么  他们为什么这么做
What? Why would they do that?
掩饰那六台发电机在伊拉克被盗的事
To cover up the theft of six generators in Iraq.
我待会跟你详细解释
Look, I will explain the rest later,
但现在我得去拿到那封信
but right now I need to get that letter.
我会带你尽可能接近拉波因特的办公室
I'll take you as far as Lapointe's office.
但剩下的就靠你自己了
But then the rest is up to you.
谢谢
Thank you.
你不是狱警
You're not a guard.
你也不是恐怖份子
And you're not a terrorist.
我知道你在伊拉克救了玛丽亚的命
We know you saved Maria's life in Iraq.
我们是来还人情的
We're here to return the favor.
这就是你们救我的原因
That's why you're helping me?
这么说吧  我们都知道抛下别人的感觉
Let's just say we all know what it's like to leave someone behind.
我爱玛丽亚  一见钟情
I love Maria. From the first time I met her.
她现在在哪儿
Where is she now?
她去联合国总部取证据
She's headed to the U.N. to get evidence
要扳倒拉波因特和戴维斯
to bring down Lapointe and Davis.
前提是他们还没逮住她
But not if they get to her first.
我们得尽快把她救出来
We've got to get her out of there before it's too late.
你当真是建议我们闯入联合国吗
Are you really suggesting we break into the United Nations?
他们有三层安保系统
They have triple-layered security.
红外线摄像机加运动探测器
Infrared cameras with motion detection.
我有办法
I have an idea.
不过需要点烟雾
But it's going to require a smoke screen
外加一辆超大卡车
and a big-ass truck.
我在联合国大厦外边
I'm in position outside the U.N. Compound.
得加油了  里瑟
Gonna need to step on it, Reese.
这边准备好了
Ready on this end.
来吧  妹子
Open wide, sister.
四楼有烟雾报告
There's a report of smoke on the fourth floor.
呼叫911
Call 911.
消防队到了
Fire department's already here.
我们需要紧急疏散
We need to evacuate the building.
别再乱按喇叭了  莱奈尔
Stop playing with the horn, Lionel.
我小时候
Ever since I was a kid,
就一直想开这个
I always wanted to drive one of these things.
给  你用得上
Here, you're gonna need this.
你和谁提过拉波因特吗
Have you told anyone about Lapointe?
信的原件一定在这儿
The original of the letter has to be here somewhere.
我们还是见好就收  快走吧
We should stop while we're ahead.
不还奥马尔一个清白  我不会离开
I am not leaving until I clear Omar's name.
戴维斯那边有消息吗  芬奇
Find anything on Davis, Finch?
他似乎删掉了所有的电邮联络人
Seems he's deleted all his email correspondence.
格罗夫斯小姐  我现在有点忙
Ms. Groves, I'm a bit occupied at the moment.
试试"哈伯门"  哈罗德
Try "Habur Gate", Harold.
"哈伯门"
"Habur Gate"?
什么意思
What does that mean?
我不知道
I don't know.
不过不用谢
But you're welcome.
还有
And, by the way...
借你家狗一用
I'm borrowing your dog.
海关清关
Customs clearance.
六台发电机
Six generators.
订购人
Requested by...
不
Oh, no.
火灾在哪儿啊  [法语]我的朋友
Where's the fire, mes amis?
这儿
Here.
-我找到了  -太好了
- I found it. - Good.
我们快走
We should go.
他随时会回来
He could be here any minute.
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
我接到保安电话
I should have known it was you
就该猜到是你
when I received a call from the guards.
你在这儿干什么
And what are you doing here?
[法语]抱歉  拉波因特先生
Excusez-moi, Monsieur Lapointe,
[法语]请原谅有点混乱  难免的
Pardonnez des désordres, c'était... inévitable.
我都不知道你懂法语
I didn't know you spoke French.
这是加入外籍兵团的第一收获
That's the first thing they teach you in the Foreign Legion.
这就当是为我朋友报仇吧
Consider this payback for what you did to my friend.
笑什么
What's so funny?
第二发往往比第一发更精准
Second round is always more accurate than the first.
什么第二发
What second round?
你连枪都没有
You're not even holding a gun.
不是说我
I wasn't talking about me.
[法语]抱歉
Excusez-moi!
仇报得差不多了
So much for payback.
快走  快走
Come on, come on.
真是遗憾啊
It's a shame, really.
毕竟我帮了你不少
After all I did to help you.
你跟戴维斯一伙的  为什么
You're working with Davis? Why?
你根本不了解真实的世界
You don't understand how the real world works.
而我早就懂了
I learned a long time ago,
在外籍兵团中被派到卢旺达时就懂了
as a Legionnaire based in Rwanda.
他们要我们去保护种族屠杀的罪犯
They used us to protect those who committed genocide.
真实的政治
Real politiks.
这是贪婪  不是政治
This is about greed, not politics.
你毫无忠诚
You have no loyalty.
看看忠诚把你害成什么样
Look at where your loyalty has landed you.
知道死在联合国大楼最惨的是什么
You know the worst thing about dying on a U.N. property?
治外法权
Extraterritorial privileges.
纽约警察很难进行调查
Makes it very difficult for the NYPD to investigate.
有人呼叫911吗
Somebody call 911?
放下武器
Drop the gun.
否则呢  警探
Or what, Detective?
否则打你个落花流水春去也
Or I'm gonna get realpolitik-y on your ass.
你和戴维斯从伊拉克偷了发电机
You and Davis stole the generators from Iraq.
你没有证据
You have no proof.
"哈伯门"  有印象吗
"Habur Gate" ring a bell?
哈伯门是伊拉克和土耳其交界处的边境检查点
Habur Gate: that's the border crossing between Iraq and Turkey.
下次找别人签海关表格
Next time have someone else sign the customs form.
猜猜看
Go figure.
外交豁免权不能止血啊
Turns out immunity doesn't stop you from bleeding.
这才叫"外交手段"
That's what I call "diplomacy."
玛丽亚
Maria.
我的上帝  你在这儿
Oh, my God, I can't believe you're here!
快点吧  小子们
Gonna need to step it up, boys.
听着像是突击队来了
Sounds like the cavalry's on its way.
-快  走吧  -得走了
- Come on. Let's go. - We gotta go!
土耳其
摩苏尔大坝
物品搜索  水力发电机
水力集团2701系列  数量: 6
搜索发电机            当前位置:
哈伯门
迪亚巴克尔
阿什卡莱
阿克恰阿巴德港
未知
你怎么找到这里的
How'd you find this place?
有人推荐这里的景色
Someone recommended the view.
高级专员办公室送过来的
The office of the high commissioner just sent this over.
恭喜
Congratulations.
你的庇护申请正式批准了
Your asylum's officially been approved.
斯凡呢
And Sevon?
希腊废除了他的外交豁免权
Greece revoked his diplomatic immunity.
纽约警局以谋杀拉波因特的罪名将其逮捕
NYPD arrested him for the murder of Lapointe.
谢谢你  警探  还有你的朋友
Thank you, Detective, and your friends.
谢谢你们做的一切
For everything.
纽约欢迎你
Welcome to New York.
怎么了
What's up?
案子不是结了吗
Thought the case was closed.
今晚干得不错  莱奈尔
You did good tonight, Lionel.
来杯香槟  要最好的
Glass of champagne, best you got.
你不是不喝酒吗
I thought you didn't drink.
三月二十
March 20th.
波斯新年
Persian New Year.
你不是不关心他国文化吗
I thought you didn't care about foreign cultures.
这就是纽约最棒的一点
That's what's great about New York.
无须环游世界去了解各国文化
You don't have to travel to learn about other cultures.
他们会送上门来
They all come here.
我父亲第一次约会就带我妈来的这儿
My father brought my mother here on their first date.
真的啊
No kidding.
好地方
Nice place.
名字换了又换
It's changed names a couple times,
但景色还是一如往昔
but the view's still the same.
走开  弗斯科
Get outta here, Fusco.
新年快乐  萨姆恩
Happy New Year, Sameen.
虽然没有沙漠的星星
It may not be the desert stars,
但什么也美不过纽约的夜空
but there's nothing like the New York city skyline.
戴维斯呢
And Davis?
据弗斯科警探的消息
According to Detective Fusco,
他逃了
he's flown the coop.
凭借他的国际关系
And with his international connections...
他可能逃去任何地方
he could be anywhere.
或许我们的某位盟友能找到他的下落
Maybe one of our allies will scoop him up.
说到盟友
Speaking of allies...
但愿根没有喂小熊吃巧克力
I do hope that Root isn't feeding bear any chocolate.
巧克力中的可可碱对狗是致命的
[荷兰语]坐  坐
Zit. Zit.
你要的发电机我办妥了
I've secured the generators you were looking for.
上周从[土耳其]阿克恰阿巴德港运出
They shipped from Akcaabat port last week.
你这是要给什么供电  整个纽约城吗
What are you trying to power? New York city?
你朋友斯凡的事我很遗憾
Sorry to hear about your friend Sevon.
不过也无妨
But just as well.
他为之工作的机构已经过时了
He worked for an antiquated institution.
真不敢相信联合国居然还以为
Hard to believe that Nation States still think
自己有影响力  能促进合作
they have any influence, even in cooperation.
斯凡疏忽了
Sevon got sloppy.
我不能容忍这种疏忽
I can't afford such liabilities.
好在我很小心
Then lucky for me I'm careful.
确实
Indeed.
走
Walk.
切断监控
Go blind.
信号丢失
追踪主体
化名  格里尔  约翰
监控摄像头离线
切换至音频
追踪主体
化名  格里尔  约翰
重量
84.024公斤
间隔
1.023秒
距离
0.976米
音频输入饱和
失去目标
转换到GPS
搜索中...
哪边  小熊
Which way, bear?
乖
That a boy.
你好啊  格罗夫斯女士
Hello, Ms. Groves.
[荷兰语]坐
Zit, boy.
我很赞赏你的跟踪能力
I commend your tracking abilities.
嗅觉往往是最容易被忽略的五感之一
Sense of smell is often the most neglected of the five senses.
也是机器唯一无法复制的
And one which machines can't replicate.
至少  现在还不能
At least...not yet.
我小时候  家里养了一条猎狐犬
When I was a boy, we had a foxhound called--
"丘吉尔"
Churchill.
我们切入正题好吗
Shall we cut to the chase?
你手里有一些不属于你的东西
You have some things that don't belong to you--
两个硬盘  一片超导芯片
two hard drives, a superconducting chip,
还有六台发电机
and six generators.
说明
Which means,
要么你打算激活"撒马利亚人"
either your planning to bring Samaritan online...
要么你就是世界上最有斗志的游戏玩家
or you're the world's most ambitious gamer.
何必浪费时间谈这些小打小闹呢
Why waste time arguing about small battles,
我们明明可以聊聊真正的战争
when we could be discussing the larger war?
也许你我之间有很多共鸣
Perhaps you and I have more in common than you think.
恕难认同
I don't think so.
我想要放机器自由
I want the machine to be free.
而你想要控制它
You wanna control it.
我就不跟你絮叨
I won't bore you with academic theories
竞争文明的学术理论了
about competing civilizations.
掌控手段获取财富是人类的本性  不是吗
It's human nature to want to control the means to wealth, hmm?
不管是盐  黄金  或是石油
Whether it be salt or gold or oil.
或是信息
Or information.
信息是新货币
It is the new currency.
既然有人要掌控
And if someone's gonna control it,
那不如是你吗
it might as well be you?
想象一下
Imagine...
如果你我长期合作
What it would be like to merge, permanently.
我需要你这种人才
I could use someone with such capabilities.
我何必呢
And why would I do that?
因为我知道你了解的是真相  格罗夫斯女士
Because I know what you know to be true, Ms. Groves, hmm?
人人都以为你疯了
Everyone thinks you're crazy.
但我不
But I don't.
因为我们理解未来
Because we understand what's coming.
理解将要发生什么
What's about to happen.
不是吗
Don't we?
你凭什么以为自己有立场跟我谈判呢
And what makes you think you're in any position to negotiate?
漂亮
Touche.
每每令我掩面长息的是
I never feel civilized...
谈判被人用枪指着
negotiating from the end of a barrel.
或是用枪指着别人
Either end.
这次就算平局好吗
Shall we call this one a draw?
很好
Very well.
也许下次见面
Perhaps next time we meet
你会重新考虑我的提议
you'll reconsider my offer.